Guide to the Rebecca Patt Cohen Collection of Labor Ephemera WAG.368
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rebecca Patt Cohen Collection of Labor Ephemera
1887-1982
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cohen, Rebecca Patt
Gallers, Donna
WAG.368
1.5 linear feet in 1 flat box and 1 half manuscript box
Rebecca Patt Cohen (1941-2020) was a teacher in the New York City schools, a coordinator for the first American Gathering of Jewish Holocaust Survivors, Program Director for the Workmen's Circle, and Program Director for the Jewish Community Council of Yonkers. She, along with her second husband Joe Cohen, was an avid collector of postcards, ephemera, and objects concerning labor, Judaica, and local Bronx and Brooklyn history. Patt Cohen was the daughter of immigrants who escaped Nazi-occupied Europe and settled in the Amalgamated Housing Cooperative in the Bronx after obtaining visas through writer and activist Jacob Pat (Patt Cohen's grandfather) and the Jewish Labor Committee. The Rebecca Patt Cohen Collection of Labor Ephemera (dated 1887-1982) consists of materials collected by Patt Cohen documenting the labor movement and Progressive Jewish social movements. Materials include union membership cards, AFL-CIO convention delegate badges, postcards and stereoscopes of labor movement parades and demonstrations, a war ration book, union patches, matchbook covers, and a Black Miss Union Made doll. Workmen's Circle is well represented through postcards, a Yiddish constitution, and flags and pennants. This collection also includes objects created and distributed by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the Women's American ORT (Organization for Rehabilitation through Training), which document the gendered forms of outreach and publicity employed by garment workers' unions, such as purses, aprons, nail files, and jewelry.
Scope and Contents
The Rebecca Patt Cohen Collection of Labor Ephemera (dated 1887-1982) consists of materials collected by Patt Cohen documenting the labor movement and Progressive Jewish social movements. Materials include union membership cards, AFL-CIO convention delegate badges, postcards and stereoscopes of labor movement parades and demonstrations, a war ration book, union patches, matchbook covers, and a Black Miss Union Made doll. Workmen's Circle is well represented through postcards, a Yiddish constitution, and flags and pennants. This collection also includes objects created and distributed by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the Women's American ORT (Organization for Rehabilitation through Training), which document the gendered forms of outreach and publicity employed by garment workers' unions, such as purses, aprons, nail files, and jewelry.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has been rehoused and arranged roughly by format.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Donna Gallers in October 2021; the accession number associated with this gift is 2021.064.
Biographical Note
Rebecca Patt Cohen (1941-2020) was a teacher in the New York City schools, a coordinator for the first American Gathering of Jewish Holocaust Survivors, Program Director for the Workmen's Circle, and Program Director for the Jewish Community Council of Yonkers. She, along with her second husband Joe Cohen, was an avid collector of postcards, ephemera, and objects concerning labor, Judaica, and local Bronx and Brooklyn history. Patt Cohen was the daughter of immigrants who escaped Nazi-occupied Europe and settled in the Amalgamated Housing Cooperative in the Bronx after obtaining visas through writer and activist Jacob Pat (Patt Cohen's grandfather) and the Jewish Labor Committee.
Clothing workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Labor movement.; Labor unions; Women in the labor movement -- United States; Textile workers -- Labor unions.; Socialism -- United States -- 20th century.; Jews -- Political activity -- United States.; Jews -- United States -- Societies, etc.; Lapel pins; Printed ephemera.; Gallers, Donna; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Workmen's Circle (U.S.)
- Ephemera, Union Maid Doll, circa 1940s-1982 (Box 1)
- Stamps, 1927-1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Labor Day Parade Stereoscopes; Photographic Prints, 1887-1906, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Workmen's Circle Postcards, 1909-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Working Cards, 1905-1919, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Memo Books -- ILGWU and Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- War Ration Book and Relief Fund Card, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Cartoons, Ephemera, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Clippings in Yiddish, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Notepads, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)